My name is Mr. Brown and this is
(TurboScribe.ai로 음성 변환됨. 이 메시지를 제거하려면 무제한으로 이용하세요.) 제 이름은 브라운 선생님이고 이것은
a video for my second grade language class
제 2학년 언어 수업을 위한 비디오입니다.
during the coronavirus quarantine in Comayagua, Honduras.
온두라스 코마야과에서의 코로나 격리 기간 동안에요.
Hello everybody, I hope all of you are
안녕하세요, 여러분. 모두
happy and that you are washing your hands.
행복하고 손을 잘 씻고 있기를 바라요.
Today our objective is to spell common verbs
오늘 우리의 목표는 흔한 동사들의 철자를 쓰고
and pronounce them correctly by watching a slideshow
슬라이드 쇼를 보면서 그것들을 정확하게 발음하고
and writing the words together.
단어들을 함께 써보는 거예요.
Does anybody know what a verb is?
동사가 무엇인지 아는 사람 있나요?
A verb is an action word.
동사는 움직임을 나타내는 말이에요.
Do you remember when we played Simon Says
우리가 '사이먼 가라사대' 게임 했던 거 기억나요?
a couple of weeks ago?
몇 주 전에요?
Yes?
네?
What are some of the words that you
'사이먼 가라사대'에서 배운 단어들
learned from Simon Says?
중에 어떤 것들이 있었죠?
Here are some that I remember.
제가 기억하는 몇 가지는 이래요.
Play, walk, run, eat, jump, stomp, clap,
Play, walk, run, eat, jump, stomp, clap,
drink, read, write, sit, close, open.
drink, read, write, sit, close, open.
Do you know any others?
다른 것도 아는 거 있나요?
Do you remember more?
더 기억나는 거 있어요?
Let's practice together some more.
같이 좀 더 연습해 봐요.
I will test you on your pronunciation later.
나중에 발음 시험 볼 거예요.
For this activity, you're going to need a
이 활동을 위해서는 연필과
pencil and a piece of paper.
종이 한 장이 필요해요.
Watch the images and write the word for
그림들을 보고 여러분이 보는 그림에
the images that you see.
해당하는 단어를 쓰세요.
When you understand the images, you will be
그림들을 이해하게 되면, 여러분은
able to play a communication game with your
반 친구들과 의사소통 게임을 할 수
classmates.
있을 거예요.
Let's do this activity together first.
먼저 이 활동을 같이 해봐요.
Okay, number one is clap, clap,
자, 1번은 clap, clap (박수치다)이에요.
like that.
이렇게요.
Number two, number two is close,
2번, 2번은 close (닫다)예요.
close, like that.
close, 이렇게요.
Number three, number three is drink, drink,
3번, 3번은 drink (마시다)예요, drink,
drink, drink.
drink, drink.
Number four is eat,
4번은 eat (먹다)이에요.
eat, eat, eat.
eat, eat, eat.
Number five is jump, j-u-m-p.
5번은 jump (점프하다)예요, j-u-m-p.
J-u-m-p, j-u-m-p.
J-u-m-p, j-u-m-p.
Number six is open, o-p, open,
6번은 open (열다)이에요, o-p, open,
open.
open.
Number seven, play, p-l-a-y.
7번, play (놀다/연주하다)예요, p-l-a-y.
Number eight, number eight is read, r-e
8번, 8번은 read (읽다)예요, r-e
-a-d, read.
-a-d, read.
Number nine, number nine is run, n
9번, 9번은 run (달리다)이에요, n
-r-u-n.
-r-u-n.
Number 10 is sit, s-i
10번은 sit (앉다)이에요, s-i
-t, not e, not seat, s-i-t,
-t, e가 아니에요, seat가 아니라, s-i-t,
sit.
sit.
Number 11, 11 is stomp, s-t,
11번, 11번은 stomp (쿵쿵거리며 걷다)예요, s-t,
stomp.
stomp.
Number 12 is walk, walk.
12번은 walk (걷다)예요, walk.
This letter is silent, walk.
이 글자는 소리가 안 나요, walk.
Last one, number 13, 13, write, write.
마지막 거, 13번, 13번, write (쓰다)예요, write.
This letter is silent, write.
이 글자는 소리가 안 나요, write.